Frank Ormsby papers, circa 1967-2004
Emory University
- The Honest Ulsterman literary materials, 1967-1990, Series 2; Boxes 5-16; OP 1 - 5
  - Ulsterman Publications, Subseries 2.4; Box 15-Box 16: folders 1-3; OP4
    - Printer's block of cover image, number 37 [January / February 1973] (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Printer's block of cover image, number 50 [Winter 1975] (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Printer's block of unidentified man [undated] (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Printed material about The Honest Ulsterman, Subseries 2.5; Box 16: folders 4-9; OP5
    This smaller subseries contains an assortment of articles and reviews about both The Honest Ulsterman magazine and Ulsterman Publication. In particular, many of the texts address the significance of the journal for Northern Irish literary culture.
    - Frazier, Adrian: " The Honest Ulsterman and the Ulster Renaissance," [interview with James Simmons] in The Literary Review, Winter 1979 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Craig, Patricia, " The Honest Ulsterman's Twenty-fifth Anniversary," in TLS, 4 June 1993 (Box OP5)
    - Flyer for The Honest Ulsterman's 25th Birthday Party Guest List (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Untitled essay on the history of The Honest Ulsterman (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous The Honest Ulsterman materials (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Articles about The Honest Ulsterman (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous promotional materials for The Honest Ulsterman (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Writings by Frank Ormsby, 1970-1995, Series 3; Boxes 17-29; OP6-9, 20
  The series for writings by Ormsby includes manuscript and typescript drafts as well as galley proofs of writing in poetry or prose. The series also contains the scripts used in the broadcasts of various radio-plays, readings, and lectures. Additionally, all materials related to books Ormsby edited are located here. This series shows the development of individual works or volumes up to the point of publication. Published items are then arranged in the printed material series.
  The poetry subseries (3.1) contains notes, manuscript, and typescript drafts of published and unpublished poems from 1970 to 1995. The published works are arranged chronologically according to major volume. Under each volume's heading, the poems are listed alphabetically. These folders include manuscript (MS) and/or typescript (TS) versions of the poems. Note that brackets often include other relevant information regarding variant titles, dates of creation, or relationships to other works. Many works are cross-referenced with others. Drafts of different poems are included in the same folder when there is no way of separating the poems. In this case, a poem's title might be listed without a box or folder number. A note in brackets will then refer the reader to the relevant folder where the document in question can be found. Typescripts and proofs of entire volumes are included at the end of each volume's subsection to roughly demonstrate the chronological development of a published volume.
  Ormsby's prose is collected in a distinct subseries (3.2) where works are then arranged by type. There are subsections for fiction, autobiographical prose, reviews, essays, speeches, and interviews. Notes after individual items indicate where and when the work was published if that information is available. Thus, many works are cross-referenced with the subseries for Ormsby's printed or published material. Because of the number of scripts and because Ormsby has been involved with broadcast presentations from 1970 to 1989, these are gathered in a separate subseries (3.3).
  Materials in the subseries (3.4) pertaining to the anthologies edited by Ormsby are arranged chronologically, like the poetry, by individual book. All items relating to the production of a specific text are presented in an order that gestures to the stages in the book's production. This subseries contains varied materials including research notes or lists of works under consideration for inclusion, actual manuscript or typescript submissions, photocopied published texts, as well as Ormsby's drafts of tables of contents, forewords, introductions, and indexes.
  Organized into four subseries: (3.1) Poetry by Frank Ormsby, (3.2) Prose by Frank Ormsby, (3.3) Scripts by Frank Ormsby, and (3.4) Works edited by Frank Ormsby.
  - Poetry by Frank Ormsby, 1970-1995, Subseries 3.1; Boxes 17-22
    This subseries showcases Frank Ormsby's long and varied career as a poet. Notebooks from the early 1970's contain drafts of many of his earliest published poems as well as very interesting prose synopses or descriptions of other poems. Published poems are arranged chronologically by volume; poems in individual volumes are listed alphabetically. A separate subsection includes typescripts of volumes that were proposed for publication but ultimately went unpublished. A large number of unpublished poems are presented alphabetically. Many of these poems are dated by Ormsby. In some cases, notes indicate that particular texts are linked to others that are more readily dated. There are also a large number of untitled manuscript and typescript fragments roughly arranged chronologically by several-year periods.
    Organized into three sections: (3.1a) Notebooks, (3.1b) Collected poetry, and (3.1c) Uncollected poetry.
    - Notebooks, 1970-1975, Subseries 3.1a; Box 17: folders 1-2
      - Poetry notebook 1970-1972 [includes synopsis of contents] (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Poetry notebook 1972-1975 [includes synopsis of contents] (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Collected poetry, 1970-1995, Subseries 3.1b; Box 17: folder 3 - Box 20: folder 7
      - Ripe for Company (1971)
      - "Back Road," TS (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - "Growing Up," TS (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - "In Memoriam," MS, TS (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - "Loughside," TS (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - "Marriage Letter," TS [a part of "Three Portraits"] (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - "McQuade," TS [a part of "Three Portraits"] (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - "On Devenish Island," MS, TS (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - "Poem: For P. McC.," TS [a part of "Three Portraits"] [See also Subseries 3.1c: Uncollected poetry, "Derrycullen Churchyard" for MS] (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - "Poem for Paula," TS [included with "Three Domestic Poems"] (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "Spoilt Child," MS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Ripe for Company, "Marriage Letter"] (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Ripe for Company, TS [incomplete; includes: "On Devenish Island," "Castlecoole," "Growing Up," "Loughside," "Island Honeymoon," "Island Honeymoon," "Virgins," "Poems for Paula," "Hairy Horseworm," "In Memoriam," "Second Childhood"] (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Ripe for Company, mock-up (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Business as Usual (1973)
      - "Amelia Street," TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "In Great Victoria Street"] (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - "Blind Raifteiri," TS [variant title: "Raifteiri"] (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - "Business as Usual," MS, TS [included with "Interim"] (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - "Elegy," TS [this poem is different from "Elegy" in uncollected poems] (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - "Floods," TS (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - "In Great Victoria Street," TS [includes: "The Belfast Pure Ice and Cold Storage Co. Ltd.," "The Crown," "Amelia Street," "The Great Northern Railway"] (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - "Interim," MS, TS [included with "Business as Usual"] (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - "Kathleen," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Store of Candles, "Floods"] (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - "The Lady Next Door," MS [See Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Donne"] (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - "Old Man on a Country Bus," TS [included as a poetry presentation, circa 1977, with: "The Practical Farms," "Wet Leaves," "Sheepman," "My Friend Havelock Ellis," "Ornaments," "Winter Offerings," "The Barracks," "Spot the Ball," "Floods," "Passing the Crematorium," "Under the Stairs"] (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - "Relief Map," [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Elegy"; Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby, "The Relief Map"]
      - "Sheepman," TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Elegy"] and A Store of Candles, "Sheepman"] (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - "Windows," TS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Elegy"]
      - "Winter Offerings," MS, TS (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Business as Usual, mock-up (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - A Store of Candles (1977)
      - A Store of Candles, tables of contents (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - "After Mass," MS, TS (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - "Aftermath," MS, TS (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - "The Air-Raid Shelter," MS, TS [variant title: "An American Camp in Ireland"] [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Store of Candles, "Illumination"] (Box 17, Folder 31)
      - "At the Reception," TS [variant title: "A Toast"] (Box 17, Folder 32)
      - "Backroads," MS (Box 17, Folder 33)
      - "The Barracks," MS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Old Man on a Country Bus"] (Box 17, Folder 34)
      - "Calendars," MS (Box 17, Folder 35)
      - "Caves," MS, TS (Box 17, Folder 36)
      - "A Death in the Mansion," MS (Box 17, Folder 37)
      - "The Edge of War," MS (Box 17, Folder 38)
      - "Fanfares," MS, TS [includes: "Factory Girl"] [variant title: "The Factory Girls"] (Box 17, Folder 39)
      - "The Farm Under the Floor," TS [includes: "Night on the Estate" and "Smokeless Fuel" [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Store of Candles, "Caves"] (Box 17, Folder 40)
      - "Floods," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Old Man on a Country Bus"] (Box 17, Folder 41)
      - "Illumination," MS, TS (Box 17, Folder 42)
      - "In Lieu of Carols," MS, TS (Box 17, Folder 43)
      - "In Memoriam," MS, TS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Ripe for Company, "In Memoriam"]
      - "Islands," MS (Box 17, Folder 44)
      - "Landscape with Figures," MS (Box 17, Folder 45)
      - "The Leaf," MS (Box 17, Folder 46)
      - "Love on the Coast," MS (Box 17, Folder 47)
      - "Mantovani at the Mental Hospital," MS (Box 17, Folder 48)
      - "The Massage Parlour," MS (Box 17, Folder 49)
      - "McQuade," MS, TS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Ripe for Company, "McQuade"]
      - "Moving In," MS (Box 17, Folder 50)
      - "My Friend Havelock Ellis," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Old Man on a Country Bus"] (Box 17, Folder 51)
      - "Natural History Selection," MS (Box 17, Folder 52)
      - "Old Man on a Country Bus," TS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Old Man on a Country Bus"]
      - "Ornaments," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Old Man on a Country Bus"] (Box 17, Folder 53)
      - "Passing the Crematorium," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Old Man on a Country Bus"] (Box 17, Folder 54)
      - "The Police Museum," MS (Box 17, Folder 55)
      - "The Practical Farms," MS [includes sections: 1) "The Small Ads," 2) "Economies," and 3) "A Fly in the Winter"] [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Old Man on a Country Bus"] (Box 17, Folder 56)
      - "The School Hockey Team in Amsterdam," MS, TS (Box 17, Folder 57)
      - "Sheepman," MS, TS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual "Sheepman" and "Old Man on a Country Bus"]
      - "Spot the Ball," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Store of Candles, "Natural History Section," and for TS See also Business as Usual, "Old Man on a Country Bus"] (Box 17, Folder 58)
      - "Stone," MS, TS (Box 17, Folder 59)
      - "Under the Stars," MS [for TS See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Old Man on a Country Bus"] (Box 17, Folder 60)
      - "Wet Leaves," MS [for TS See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Old Man on a Country Bus"] (Box 17, Folder 61)
      - "Winter Offerings," MS, TS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Business as Usual, "Winter Offerings" and "Old Man on a Country Bus"]
      - Being Walked by a Dog (1978)
      - "The Bees' Nest," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - "Being Walked By a Dog," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - "The Heart of It," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - "Heavy Lorries," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - "Last Night," MS, TS [variant title: "Last night I looked towards you in a dream…"] (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - "The Ownership of the Lough," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - "The Parting," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - "A Small Town in Ireland," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - "Waiting for a Connection," TS (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - "Where She Lives," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - A Northern Spring (1986)
      - A Northern Spring, research correspondence (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - A Northern Spring, research notes (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring," research notes (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - A Northern Spring, notebook with manuscripts, February - July 1983 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - "After the Depression," MS, TS [also includes MS of "For the Record" and "McCook, Nebraska"] (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - "Among the Dead," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - "Apples, Normandy, 1944," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - "At the Jaffé Memorial Fountain, Botanic Gardens," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - "The Bees' Nest," TS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), Being Walked by a Dog, "The Bees' Nest"]
      - "Between the Lines," MS (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - "Bridie," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - "The Clearing," MS [for TS, See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - "Cleo, Oklahoma," TS (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - "The Convoy," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - "A Cross on a White Circle," TS (Box 18, Folder 24)
      - "Dailies," MS, TS [variant title: "Newspapers"] (Box 18, Folder 25)
      - "Darkies," MS, TS [variant title: "Chocolate Soldiers"] (Box 18, Folder 26)
      - "Dayton, Ohio," MS (Box 18, Folder 27)
      - "The Diary," MS [variant titles: "Rice" and "A Reading at Bang Pan"] (Box 18, Folder 28)
      - "Duffy's Basement Bar," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 29)
      - "Felix Peccione's Crucifixion," MS (Box 18, Folder 30)
      - "The Flamethrower," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 31)
      - "For the Record," TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "After the Depression"] (Box 18, Folder 32)
      - "From the German," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 33)
      - "The Gardner's Help," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 34)
      - "Grenade-Fishing in the Orne," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 35)
      - "Home," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 36)
      - "Home and Away," MS [variant title: "Brackwede"] (Box 18, Folder 37)
      - "I Died in a Country Lane," TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 38)
      - "I Stepped on a Landmine," TS [variant title: "I Stepped on a Small Landmine"] [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 39)
      - "Incurables," TS (Box 18, Folder 40)
      - "King William Park," TS (Box 18, Folder 41)
      - "Lesson of the War," TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 42)
      - "Liberation," MS, TS [variant title: "Refugees"] (Box 18, Folder 43)
      - "Maimed Civilians, Isigny," MS, TS [variant titles: "We Did Not See the Wreckage" and "Civilian Casualties"] (Box 18, Folder 44)
      - "McConnell's Birthday," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 45)
      - "McCook, Nebraska," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "After the Depression"] (Box 18, Folder 46)
      - "My Memory Collected Places," MS, TS [variant title: "My Part of the World"] (Box 18, Folder 47)
      - "News from Home," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 48)
      - "The Night I Lost World War II," MS, TS [variant title: "Lucky"] (Box 18, Folder 49)
      - "A Northern Spring," TS [numbered sequence includes: "1. The Clearing," "2. McConnell's Birthday," "4. Lesson of the War," "5. The Third Day Out," "6. The Padre," "7. I Died in a Country Lane," "8. Bridie," "9. I Stepped On a Small Landmine," "10. Seaplanes at Castle Archdale," "11. Grenade Fishing in the Orne," "14. The Gardener's Help," "15. Duffy's Basement Bar," "16. The Convoy," "20. Postscripts"] (Box 18, Folder 50)
      - "On Devenish Island," TS (Box 18, Folder 51)
      - "The Padre," TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 52)
      - "Postscripts," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 53)
      - "Return to California," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 54)
      - "Safe Home," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 55)
      - "Seaplanes at Castle Archdale," MS, TS [variant title: "The Radio Station"] [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 18, Folder 56)
      - "Soldier Bathing," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 57)
      - "Some of Us Stayed Forever," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 58)
      - "Ste-Mère-Eglise," MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 59)
      - "Street Life: 2 Slum Terrace," MS [variant titles: "The Flats" and "The Grandchildren"], "Street Life: 3 Mechanics," TS (Box 18, Folder 60)
      - "Survivors," TS (Box 18, Folder 61)
      - "They Buried Me in an Orchard," TS (Box 18, Folder 62)
      - "Travelling," MS [variant title: "My Grandmother's French Journal"] (Box 18, Folder 63)
      - "The War Photographers," TS (Box 18, Folder 64)
      - A Northern Spring, unidentified manuscript fragments (Box 18, Folder 65)
      - A Northern Spring, title pages, MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 66)
      - A Northern Spring, tables of contents, MS, TS (Box 18, Folder 67)
      - A Northern Spring, proofs (Box 18, Folder 68)
      - The Ghost Train (1995)
      - "Action Replays," MS, TS [variant title: "Brothers in White"] (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - "The All Ireland Campaign," MS, TS [variant titles: "Foot Culture," "On the Sideline"] (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - "At the Smugglers' Restaurant, Carrick Fergus," MS, TS [variant title: "In the Smugglers' Restaurant"] (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - "At Stoke Poges," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - "Audience Participation," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - "The Charlotte Gibson Bed," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - "Come as You Are," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - "The Crossing," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - "The Easter Ceasefire," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - "From The Memoirs (after Francois Vidocq)," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - "The Gap on My Shelf," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - "The Gatecrasher," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), The Ghost Train, "Travellers"] (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - "Geography," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), The Ghost Train, "Travellers"] (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - "The Ghost Train," TS (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - "The Graveyard School," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - "The Heart," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - "Helen," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - "Helen Keller," TS (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - "In Retrospect," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - "Lullaby," TS (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "The Names," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - "One Saturday," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - "Open House," TS (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - "A Paris Honeymoon," MS, TS [includes: "L'Orangerie," "Notre-Dame," "Versailles," "Le Père Lachaise"] (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - "Picking Winners," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - "The Photograph," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - "Reading to My Father," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 27)
      - "Roslea Hero," MS, TS [includes newspaper source] (Box 19, Folder 28)
      - "St. Valentine's Day," MS (Box 19, Folder 29)
      - "The Sons," MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 30)
      - "Three Cradle Songs," MS, TS [variant title: "For Matthew"] (Box 19, Folder 31)
      - "Travellers," MS, TS [variant title: "Locale"] (Box 19, Folder 32)
      - "Winter Sports," MS, TS [variant title: "Sport and Art"] [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), The Ghost Train, "Reading to My Father"] (Box 19, Folder 33)
      - "You, the Movie," MS, TS [variant title: "Foetal Attraction I"] (Box 19, Folder 34)
      - The Ghost Train, title page, TS [includes variant volume title: Parks and Cemeteries: Poems] (Box 19, Folder 35)
      - The Ghost Train, tables of contents, MS, TS (Box 19, Folder 36)
      - The Ghost Train, acknowledgements, TS (Box 19, Folder 37)
      - Unpublished poetry collections
      - Untitled Book Manuscript (submitted in 1970's for Gregory Award or Kavanagh Award), photocopy TS [includes: "On Devenish Island," "The Practical Farms" (sections include: "The Small Ads," "Economies," "A Fly in the Water"), "Wet Leaves," "Landscape with Figures," "Old Man on a Country Bus," "Calendars," "Crab Apples," "Green Bottles," "Tracks," "My Friend Havelock Ellis," "McQuade," "An Uncle Remembered," "At the Reception," "Virgins," "Spoilt Child," "Natural History Section," "The Leaf," "Illumination," "Interim," "Stone," "In Lieu of Carols," "Ornaments," "Winter Offerings," "The Edge of War," "The Air-Raid Shelter," "The Belfast Pure Ice and Cold Storage Co. LTD.," "Amelia Street," "Floods," "Sheepman," "Spot the Ball," "Mantovani at the Mental Hospital," "Inferno: A New Circle," "Moving-In," "Mrs. G. Watters," "Windows," "Doorstep," "Still Life," "A Visit to the Gatehouse," "The Barracks," "Under the Stairs"] (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Untitled Pamphlet (pre-1971), corrected proof [includes: "Growing Up," "Hairy Horseworm," "In Memoriam," "Loughside," "Poems for Paula II," "Poems for Paula II," "Island Honeymoon," "On Devenish Island," "Regional," "Virgins II"] [Original folder note: "Note also copy of what was to be first poetry pamphlet, already set up, but bought back from Botanic Printers because of quarrel with Tom McGurk. See McGurk's pamphlet First Born, which was first in series. It lists the other projected pamphlets—none of which appeared."] (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Working Days [ca. 1976], Tables of contents, MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring] (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - The War Photographers: Poems 1977-1983, Tables of contents, MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - The War Photographers: Poems 1977-1983, "My Careful Life," TS (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - The War Photographers: Poems 1977-1983, "The Sisters," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 6)